<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-10T17:19:40+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Recovering melancholic</title><subtitle>Chronicles of a recovering melancholic</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Magpie</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/10/magpie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Magpie" /><published>2025-11-10T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-10T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/10/magpie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/10/magpie/"><![CDATA[<p>A Magpie sat huddled on a trembling twig,<br />
its eyes flickering like candlelight—<br />
darting here, glancing there,<br />
at everything and nothing at once.<br />
Was it lonely? Or merely lost in thought?<br />
Who is to say what stirs in a bird’s heart?<br /></p>

<p>Then the morning sun shifted,<br />
and a sudden gleam pierced the air—<br />
a shimmer, a whisper,<br />
a trinket glistening on the ground below.<br />
It called to the Magpie,<br />
softly, sweetly,<br />
like a secret meant only for two.<br /></p>

<p>“But I already have so many trinkets,” murmured the mind.<br />
“None like this,” sang the heart.<br />
And with a flutter of wings,<br />
it was gone—<br />
downward, chasing wonder.<br /></p>

<p>It pecked, prodded, pondered—<br />
evaluating, hesitating,<br />
and then surrendering—<br />
falling, without knowing,<br />
into that tender illusion we call love.<br /></p>

<p>“I need this,” it cried.<br />
“This one belongs to me!<br />
My life is hollow without it.”<br />
So it clutched the treasure in its beak<br />
and soared towards its nest—<br />
only to find there was no room.<br />
No matter how it tried,<br />
the trinket would not fit<br />
among the others it once adored.<br /></p>

<p>It perched nearby, still and aching,<br />
watching light dance across the thing<br />
it could not keep.<br />
And with a sigh—<br />
it let go.<br /></p>

<p>Now it sits in its nest,<br />
day after day,<br />
looking down at that trinket,<br />
glistening still,<br />
so close,<br />
so far.<br /></p>

<p>“Foolish Magpie,” they say,<br />
“forever chasing shiny dreams,<br />
mistaking fascination for love.”<br />
But what do they know—<br />
of longing feathered and fragile,<br />
of the shimmer that stirs a soul awake?<br /></p>

<p>Would a Magpie untouched by love<br />
still dream of a trinket it cannot hold?<br />
Would it question the comfort of its nest,<br />
its own safe cage of plenty?<br />
Perhaps they are right—<br />
perhaps Magpies are meant to be silly,<br />
to love what they cannot keep,<br />
to ache for the impossible.<br /></p>

<p>And one day—<br />
when it wakes to find<br />
the trinket gone,<br />
stolen by time or by wind—<br />
that will be the day<br />
it will finally know.<br /></p>

<p>Whether it was love,<br />
or merely light.<br /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Magpie sat huddled on a trembling twig, its eyes flickering like candlelight— darting here, glancing there, at everything and nothing at once. Was it lonely? Or merely lost in thought? Who is to say what stirs in a bird’s heart?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/magpie.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/magpie.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Light</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/09/light/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Light" /><published>2025-11-09T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-09T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/09/light</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/09/light/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>We all are broken, thats how the light gets in</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We all are broken, thats how the light gets in]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/light.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/light.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Harsh</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/08/harsh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Harsh" /><published>2025-11-08T02:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-08T02:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/08/harsh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/08/harsh/"><![CDATA[<p>That was just unneccessarily harsh. Felt bad in the morning and I don’t even know why I said all of it.</p>

<p>None of that really was feedback, none of it was ever a problem. It was just plain nit-picking. I was lying in bed and reflecting, why am I nit-picking about her to myself?</p>

<p>It is just that she has moved on and living her life, and here I am still here trying to move past all of it, in some ways; tugging at old threads that keep coming out.</p>

<p>I wish I would get on already and live my life and focus on things that matter today. I think this was just a subconscious attempt to brew a mental distance from an idea and a memory.</p>

<p>It is not fair or real. But there must be a better way to do this. I am sure, I’ll figure it out, eventually. Until then, I hope she is well and happy. I hope she has forgotten about this place and she never finds that entry. Even if she ever does…</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“You should know you are perfect the way you are and there is nothing that warrants a change in you. Just be you and your deserving world will eventually find you.”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[That was just unneccessarily harsh. Felt bad in the morning and I don’t even know why I said all of it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/harsh.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/harsh.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Feedback</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/07/feedback/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feedback" /><published>2025-11-07T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-07T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/07/feedback</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/07/feedback/"><![CDATA[<p>It is the day to let it all out.</p>

<p>Another day, another trip to hospital. Hairlined ribs, in addition to the finger. I feel sad that sometimes I can only play the role of a caregiver and nothing else. Is that true though? Is that all I can do or is that what I have resigned myself to? I am sure I can do more. I can do more and then still feel, that I can possibly do more. What is important to establish is, how much <i>more</i> is <i>more enough</i>? That reflection led me to a rabbit hole, from which there was no easy coming back out.</p>

<p>I found a draft letter, that I wrote back to her right after that “feedback” conversation. The time when we were supposed to vocalize our honest feelings about each other, when we were on the cusp of parting our ways.</p>

<p>Reading it brought back some of my supressed feelings back. This is how the letter started.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I hope you are on your trip and it goes well. Safe travels and take care of your health. I incidentally picked a movie tonight where the character I hated the most was possibly me in real life. It felt a bit shameful. There are couple of things I wanted to tell you, and I have largely learnt to moderate the truth of what I think and what I feel with you, unlike several months ago, when I was almost a glass-frog. (Maybe we came full circle on that, I was an avid advocate of that and now I am possibly not). You would remember, it is one of the first things we talked about, when we found each other. Despite my better judgement I am writing down the feedback for you, that you so repeatedly requested.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It goes on to talk about the feedback I had for her. Looking back at it I am grateful to myself that sense prevailed and I just saved it as a draft and moved on. What purpose would it have served? My biggest consideration was, that for a relationship, what does parting feedback even mean? Is it an exit interview about what could have made one stay? Is it a mechanism to seek validation? Is it a mechanism to find what parts should one change about self for the next person? How do you know those parts are worth changing? How do you know next person is not going to be diamitrically opposite? How do you know that “you”, the real “you” is not good enough, and warrants a change? What gives anyone the right in the world to provide feedback and expect a change? I had a fundamental issue with the thought process. It would be eccentric of me to think that someone should change themselves because there are parts that I don’t like. People are not a living-room upholstry. It shouldn’t work like that.</p>

<p>And then I looked at the feedback that she gave me. The fact that I was broken, damaged and needed help. That I am definitely not normal. I have hurt festering inside me that I am taking out on other people and hurting them. I need professional help and therapy, as she repeated several times during the conversation. I remember that conversation went on for 30 minutes and I was mostly a listener before I was asked to share things in the same vein. I shrugged off that I did not have much to say on the topic. After that call, I was just down in the dumps for so many days. Mostly reflecting that all of it was true about me.</p>

<p>Days later, I slowly started challenging the notion that I was the only problem. I started seeing more clearly that we were truly not compatible in all the ways. I have tendency to mould myself to situation and person I exhibit love for and it can come across as compatibility, whereas it is just me being me, sometimes in an unsustainable way.</p>

<p>We never travelled together, despite so much debate. I tried planning treks or a weekend getaway in hills. The only response I remember from that conversation is how it was not value for money. And I always assumed that I was the one who was more sensitive about money. Any trip that did not have work travel and stay involved, felt expensive and <b>not worth it</b>. Why?</p>

<p>We never ate out. I persuaded and asked. She said, breakfast out was crap. Why to go? Everytime we decided on a date night, it would never happen, mostly because we had so much food at home. Because, apparently eating out is all about filling tummies. I think we made an exception once and ordered something at home. Why did we never go out for a meal together? Why?</p>

<p>What we ate? One of the early reactions in the relationship was the relief that I loved her food. I did, to be fair. But over time, thats all we ate. I genuinely had no problem, but I am surprised it was never a conversation as to how come both our eating habits and staple diets were not evolving? Only mine. Why?</p>

<p>Only I travelled mostly to bring both of us together? There was a recognition of that. So we decied to find an Airbnb in the city where I lived. Soon it became a question of safety, expensive, logistics and what not. We tried finding a place for the weekend and it felt expensive. The easiest thing was to get me to fly over. At the time I was happy to. But it does begs the question, what was the most important bit? Comfort of home, the savings, convenience, or being together? I felt the order got muddled up somethwere. Why?</p>

<p>We never found a equitable way to express love for each other while spending money. The rules were different? Why would it not be uncomfortable for me to accept something and it would be for her? Why my discomfort can be navigated but hers can’t be? Why?</p>

<p>Would she have installed a dishwasher for me? Would she leave the kitchen overnight with basic cleaning? Were any of those were up for a debate? Or the <b>minimalism</b> and the <b>better judgement</b> of doing <u>the right thing</u> would have always been the way to go? I don’t know the answer, but I would have asked this now.</p>

<p>I accept that I always seemed undecisive. Throwing spanner in there every now and then. But I would say that my undecisiveness was met by only caution. Not sheer force of love, that was so often proclaimed. When it came down to moving cities to be closer, the first, there was a sense of excitement, that slowly turned into caution that gradually transformed into a cautionary period of a year before we make a reckless decision. For everything little I did, later I wondered, what matched it from the other side. What can I look back and say, I see, this person made a sacrifice to move forward with me? I had moved out of my house and took upon a life that demanded a lot more and offered a lot less. Why was it required to wait for a year? Because I did not have a great track record at keeping my word?</p>

<p>Lets look at that part.</p>

<p>When our relationship started out. We started with basic 4 rules. Laid out by her. Emotionless hookup. Separate finances. No Jealousy. Safety. She was the first one to demonstrate jealousy without clear expectation setting and that conversation transitioned from emotional hookup to full blown romantic relationship. How? Why? She felt free to spend money on me? What about clear finances? Safety is the only one we honored, almost always. I am not saying that she was the only responsible person for all the transgressions, she was not. I was an equal part, but to be fair we both had track record of not doing what we start off with. So how come the weight of frail promises is only borne by me? I was told that our relationship need not meet the definitions of a normative relationship structure, but I don’t think that held to be true for too long. And yet, the burden of it not working out was mine to bear.</p>

<p>What did we agree on? What was the common ground? Why were we compatible? I have often wondered. Once I emerged from the guilt of leading both of us astray and decided to share the responsibility of it between two mature adults, I realized that what kept us together was also me in some ways.</p>

<p>We were not compatible, not in all the ways at least. What held us together was pure love. Now the rose tint has worn off.</p>

<p>This is not to say that our love was not real or that it has dissipated. It is only to realize that to sustain a relationship meaningfully without doubt, you need signals of long term compatibility and those were sometimes a hit and a miss.</p>

<p>But momentary love does not care about that. It just loves. But this is what I said long back -</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It is easier to love somebody than to live with them. Love is fantasy, living is work<br /></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Before writing this, I was wondering, what if she finds this entry someday, what would she say? I thought hard about it, and my response is what I said to that person yesterday.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you want to play the protagonist, write your own story, don’t hope you find that recognition in mine.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Back to tending the broken ribs now.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is the day to let it all out.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/feedback.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/feedback.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Finger</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/finger/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finger" /><published>2025-11-06T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-06T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/finger</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/finger/"><![CDATA[<p>Today ended up being a tiring day. I reached home late. The work started early. One of the difficult meetings was sitting right in middle of the day. The one where just the thought of it sucks the hope and happiness out of you. Braved it. Skipped lunch. Thought that I’d grab something in evening. Got a call about a fall. Rushed to emergency. Vitals, scans, xrays. The usual. Ended up with a cast. Came back home just in time to resume work and calls. Remembered that in the morning I had planned to skip dinner and so there was no food. Grabbed a few odd things and then the chores for children. The day flew by. Nothing meaningful got done, the list of to-dos got longer, and body grew wearier.</p>

<p>In middle of all of that. I was chatting with someone about an incident that I was part of. I had written up the situation from my perspective. The reaction to that was, this is a one sided perspective. The other sided has not been represented. The view has been conviniently tailored to strengthen my representation. Surely, there is more to it if you ask the other person.</p>

<p>I pondered on it for a few minutes. Here was my response.</p>

<p>Sure. I am not a journalist. If people want to play the role of a protagonist, then they must write their own stories. Because, I am corupptible, greedy, insolent, biased and just human.</p>

<p>And if that is not justified enough a response, then I have only one finger to spare. However broken it may be.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today ended up being a tiring day. I reached home late. The work started early. One of the difficult meetings was sitting right in middle of the day. The one where just the thought of it sucks the hope and happiness out of you. Braved it. Skipped lunch. Thought that I’d grab something in evening. Got a call about a fall. Rushed to emergency. Vitals, scans, xrays. The usual. Ended up with a cast. Came back home just in time to resume work and calls. Remembered that in the morning I had planned to skip dinner and so there was no food. Grabbed a few odd things and then the chores for children. The day flew by. Nothing meaningful got done, the list of to-dos got longer, and body grew wearier.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/finger.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/finger.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Genesis</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/genesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Genesis" /><published>2025-11-06T01:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-06T01:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/genesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/genesis/"><![CDATA[<p>Back in cab, on my way to home. Reading old letters as I usually do at 1:30 am. Went far back when we were guessing names. I looked through the letters and I saw something that I missed as it was happening then.</p>

<p>Lookng back, I think this picture was the genesis of what we termed as “crash &amp; burn” eventually, even before it happened, from what <s>was</s> <i>could have been</i> a beautiful friendship.</p>

<p>The need to know more. The need to have more. The need to be more.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>He who is not contented with what he has, would not be contented with what he would like to have 
~Socrates</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Once of the excerpt from the letter that I enjoyed reading again.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We have graduated to life, my dear! (I have this habit of kissing the back of my right fist when I think about/talk to myself about someone who I have tender feelings for – only a couple of people in that list– I just did that writing the above sentence. That’s the sign)</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in cab, on my way to home. Reading old letters as I usually do at 1:30 am. Went far back when we were guessing names. I looked through the letters and I saw something that I missed as it was happening then.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/genesis.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/genesis.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Socks</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/05/socks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Socks" /><published>2025-11-05T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-05T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/05/socks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/05/socks/"><![CDATA[<p>There was a time when I wore only grey, black and white socks. Thick ones. Only specific brands. Mostly because I had skin sensitivity with general polyester brands. And then one day black socks started looking ugly to me. I could only deal with white and grey. But eventually moved to more colorful patterns. Maybe to represent a more versatile personality hidden under the garb of same old boring, in the plain sight.</p>

<p>One of the last things we fought about was the 4-5 pairs of socks that I received unceremoniously. I still remember how much it irked me to open that packet. Reflecting back it was less about socks. We had discussed numerous times, that in relationship, people have similar privileges. Everyone needs to express love and they have their own mechanisms. And either you can allow that freedom to express yourself even if the action to express that is in conflict with your personal principles or you can set specific boundaries. But it feels wierd if the rules are different for both people. A constant debate.</p>

<p>She expressed that she was particular. Her choice and sensibilities mattered. My choice and sensibilities could be overridden by her need to express love. It infuriated me. I failed to comprehend often, how could someone so smart, learnt, and empathetic could be so eccentric? She felt uneven setup was completely ok. What made it worse was that she would let me buy a few things every now and then with careful guidance to make me feel like that I had similar privileges.</p>

<p>When I looked at those socks, I said to myself, it has been so many years since I have worn black socks, I am never wearing these. I messaged her and told her that she was eccentric and she never really understood my perspective on it. And I was going to send these back to her. The bedsheet, towel(s), sweatshirt, handkerchiefs, shoes, underpants, toothbrush, soap, shirts; everything was laced with her personality on it. In someway, quite single mindedly. It didn’t even feel like a conversation at times, other times it did, because I resisted vehemently. The part that often irked me was the sense of superiority that came with those things. As if, she always knew better. I am not saying she didn’t. Thats beside the point, it is the arrogance that I was put off by.</p>

<p>And then the toothbrush stopped working suddenly one day. The bedsheet faded. The sweatshirt felt a bit loose. And I realized that slowly all those things were slowly fading away from my life. And then I found these socks. Still fresh, as black as they ever were and waiting on a decision from me. I decided, that when the time was there, I felt like I held my ground, and now was the time to change my mind. So I started wearing them. All my other socks have worn out. These are the primary socks I wear on most days. And everytime I look at them, they remind me of all this and confuse me. Was it really the fact that she failed to understand me on this point or was it my failed agency to accept and change? I don’t know. And now it does not matter.</p>

<p>Now, I can only <i>Sock it up!</i></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There was a time when I wore only grey, black and white socks. Thick ones. Only specific brands. Mostly because I had skin sensitivity with general polyester brands. And then one day black socks started looking ugly to me. I could only deal with white and grey. But eventually moved to more colorful patterns. Maybe to represent a more versatile personality hidden under the garb of same old boring, in the plain sight.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/socks.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/socks.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Content</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/03/content/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Content" /><published>2025-11-03T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-03T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/03/content</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/03/content/"><![CDATA[<p>Most days when I am down in the dumps I use this place to find my balance, vent out and generally spew hatred at the cosmos. However the days I am at peace, I tend to be an ungrateful prick and I don’t say much. So I thought maybe it is time to change it today.</p>

<p>While I am not at a point where I am thinking of this as a gratitude journal, even though I have enough in life to be grateful about, I think it is worth broadcasting to the void that I feel hopeful, calm and content.</p>

<p>Last few days were all about regurgigating months of pent up feelings. With all that unloaded into the abyss, I feel lighter and calmer.</p>

<p>It is easy to get tunnel-visioned on what you don’t have, to lose the sight of what you do. I remember I took this path to make best of what I have rather than what it could be. Today is a reminder of that.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most days when I am down in the dumps I use this place to find my balance, vent out and generally spew hatred at the cosmos. However the days I am at peace, I tend to be an ungrateful prick and I don’t say much. So I thought maybe it is time to change it today.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/content.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/content.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cycles</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/02/cycles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cycles" /><published>2025-11-02T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/02/cycles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/02/cycles/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been travelling. Came down to a house where I grew up in my teenage and adoloscent years. Memories rushing back from school and the time I spent in this house. I am here to be a caregiver for a person who has undergone a surgery.</p>

<p>Today seems to be generally a better day for me. Spent big part of it reflecting as to why do I operate in these cycles of hope and despair. This need for being loved and being free. Need for Solitude and detestation of lonliness. All this time the choices have always been with me and I have made them and then I have gone back to question them. Then why do I feel this lack of control? It just seems to be a perpetual cycle, like everything else in nature.</p>

<p>I was just flipping through old letters and reading the eternal promises of friendship I and she made, that seem to mean nothing now. One bound by resolution and other one by a strong sense of boundaries. Prioritising what is important to self than the other, possibly in both the cases.</p>

<p>If she put me to a test on this, what would I do? I have wondered. I am thinking about that and reflecting back on the letter I wrote to her few days back. Atleast the last part of it. Here is the paraphrased version of it.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I miss you. I am extremely sorry to have hurt you. I know I did. It is unforgivable and I understand that. Yet, I don’t think I will reach out and apologise. Apology has no meaning without amends. And I have no way or intention of making amends. I miss you because you were closest to someone I meaningfully loved in a long time. I could tell you everything. And I miss our conversation but I don’t miss the complexity of our lives. I feel free but also lonely. This is acceptable to me, on most days. Just that today is not that day. 
This is a very very selfish <i>I miss you</i>. If you came back and said that to me I wouldn’t be able to reciprocate. Like I had said, we were a perfect fit in some ways and not a fit in other. For things that are important to me in my life right now, I am not able to fit you in. And you deserve to be treated better and with more love. That is why I absolutely believe that I did the right thing by disappearing on you. Subjective and highly debatable. Sure.
I hope you are well baby (tears are rolling down just saying that word). Except an occasional reference I have not said that to anyone in such a long time. I miss saying that to you! You were such a joy! For this moment right now, I would give up everything to be with you. I miss you.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Ultimately, whenever I think about this topic of what role I have ended playing in the life of someone I genuinely cared about so much, the only rationalisation I have found for myself (mostly so that I can sleep peacefully at night) is</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It is ok to disappoint others if it means not disappointing yourself</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been travelling. Came down to a house where I grew up in my teenage and adoloscent years. Memories rushing back from school and the time I spent in this house. I am here to be a caregiver for a person who has undergone a surgery.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/cycle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/cycle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Future</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Future" /><published>2025-10-30T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-30T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/future</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/future/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Maybe I don’t exist in the future, I am so worried about</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maybe I don’t exist in the future, I am so worried about]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/future.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/future.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>