<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-30T07:29:48+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Recovering melancholic</title><subtitle>Chronicles of a recovering melancholic</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Liberated</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/29/liberated/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liberated" /><published>2025-10-29T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-29T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/29/liberated</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/29/liberated/"><![CDATA[<p>I was sleep deprived for last few days. Was travelling for work and returning to home in cab. Cab rides, remind me of me talking to her. The long chats we use to have and the frivilous things we use to say. The tired mind and lonely soul got sucked into the whirlwhind of memories.</p>

<p>In that moment, my mind was swirling with emotions. I felt reaching out and talking to her. Expressing how I was feeling. Contradictions were all over were me. I realized that I needed to let it all out but not at the cost of her or my sanity.</p>

<p>I figured for someone who has blocked me and cannot unblock me now, my letters would never be delivered to her. So I took a leap of faith and poured my heart out to her. Bared my soul into a letter. I shot it across into a void. Trembling with anxiety what if she read it? What if she received it?</p>

<p>Thankfully, atleast I think she did not, and it sits there in void. Capturing that moment of hopelessness for me. I can go back and read it. It was like capturing my emotions in a glass bottle and locking them away. Only to be admired momentarily every now and then.</p>

<p>I feel lighter having said everything that I wanted to. I feel happy to be able to say it to her and yet not to her. This is the best compromise I could have asked for. I don’t feel guilty, I don’t feel constrained.</p>

<p>I feel liberated, with a pseudo-void in my life, that is her. I don’t know how long this will last, but it works for now and that is more than what I can ask for. One step at a time.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was sleep deprived for last few days. Was travelling for work and returning to home in cab. Cab rides, remind me of me talking to her. The long chats we use to have and the frivilous things we use to say. The tired mind and lonely soul got sucked into the whirlwhind of memories.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/liberated.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/liberated.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">People</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/27/people/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People" /><published>2025-10-27T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-27T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/27/people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/27/people/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>You meet people for a reason. Either you need them to change your life or it is you who will change theirs</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You meet people for a reason. Either you need them to change your life or it is you who will change theirs]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/waiting.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/waiting.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Song In Heart</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/25/song-in-heart/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Song In Heart" /><published>2025-10-25T13:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-25T13:17:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/25/song-in-heart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/25/song-in-heart/"><![CDATA[<p>The sensor bell for his movement went off in the wee hours of the morning. I got up to help him and after helping him I found myself unable to go back to sleep. I ended up doomscrolling as usual.</p>

<p>Came across a song used as a background score by one of the videos on social media. It was a Tamil song by Iliayaaraja. This reminded me of a song that she once shared she me as one of her favourites. Unfortunately I didn’t remember the name or anything else about the song except a little context of what it was about. Thanks to the modern technology and its ability to deal with fuzzy asks, I was able to eventually find it. It was a song by Yesudas.</p>

<p>Since then the tune for both songs is stuck in my head reminding me of the long morning chats in general, over the phone before getting up. De-compressing and starting day with a conversation made mornings worth looking forward to. It has been so long that I have had a chat like that with anyone. These songs remind me of those rituals and her. Few days back I dreamt of her. I don’t remember the specifics but it was something in the context of her being indifferent to me on an airport.</p>

<p>It is funny how so many memories of her are all tied to travel, flights and airports and yet we were on an airport together maybe only once. And I remember that particular instance ended in both of us being distraught and sad. I am just glad we are not doing that to each other anymore. I continue to believe, this path has given certainty, closure and ability to move forward. Hopefully towards peace and maybe solitude.</p>

<p>One of the things a friend recently said, that helped me articulate it in a way, that I felt more at peace with it is</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Solitude is chosen, loneliness is not
~ A Friend</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sensor bell for his movement went off in the wee hours of the morning. I got up to help him and after helping him I found myself unable to go back to sleep. I ended up doomscrolling as usual.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/song-in-heart.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/song-in-heart.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Good Thing</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/24/a-good-thing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Good Thing" /><published>2025-10-24T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-24T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/24/a-good-thing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/24/a-good-thing/"><![CDATA[<p>We have parted ways for a while now. I understand I forced that upon us, so it is understandable there must be some resentment to it. I can also imagine her saying something like “<i>I won’t give anyone else in my life this much power to have that level of control on me</i>”, but I believe, the process must have required getting as far away from me as possible. I have an appreciation of it and some perspective. So nothing is shocking here.</p>

<p>We corresponded as friends for 2 years or more maybe. There were treasure trove of letters we wrote. So many things, that I visit almost everyday to just read and smile. And no matter where and how I am, I don’t have it in me to delete those.</p>

<p>I tried to contact her recently through a letter to just see if we could catch up in person over a tea to see how we have been doing. Satiate the curiosity that hits wall everyday. But what I ended up realizing is that I think she has deleted me as a friend and all the correspondence that we ever had. The fact that she deleted me is understandable, but how did she muster the will power to delete those letters. Those are some last remanents of something that was so beautiful and pure. It was honest and it was just us.</p>

<p>It made me a bit sad. But I have no qualms about it. I understand that maybe that is what was needed for her to grieve, as I have needed those letters to manage my own process through all this time.</p>

<p>But one thing that I often think about is, what Dickens posed so beautifully as a question.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Is it better to have had a good thing and lost it, or never have had it?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I think I know my answer. I didn’t realize hers would  be so different.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have parted ways for a while now. I understand I forced that upon us, so it is understandable there must be some resentment to it. I can also imagine her saying something like “I won’t give anyone else in my life this much power to have that level of control on me”, but I believe, the process must have required getting as far away from me as possible. I have an appreciation of it and some perspective. So nothing is shocking here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/a-good-thing.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/a-good-thing.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Life That Wasn’t</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/22/a-life-that-wasnt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Life That Wasn’t" /><published>2025-10-22T08:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-22T08:17:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/22/a-life-that-wasnt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/22/a-life-that-wasnt/"><![CDATA[<p>Today’s post is about someone, whom I had not known or not kept in touch with. I had a neighbour when I was growing up. Someone of my mother’s age. I remember, every night she would howl as her drunk husband would beat her up. Year after year, life delivered pain and anguish. Many years later when I had moved away from that place, I found out that in an <s>un</s>fortunate accident her drunk husband fell from a height and passed away while he was visitng someone. She had a son, and she pegged her hopes on him to reclaim a life that never was.</p>

<p>Son got married, got hooked onto drugs. Wife left him and the son beat his mother for money, who had remained the sole bread winner <s>for the family</s>. The son was almost always absent into oblivion.</p>

<p>Few months ago, due to a municipal mishap she consumed contaminated water. Misread her medication and consumed it such that all her organs failed slowly while her son was no where to be seen. She battled slow death on her own in the slient corners of the humble abode that she had.</p>

<p>Another life, scarred, forgotten and uncared for. I was not particularly close to her. But when I heard this I felt extreme sadness. I felt like there is no one to remember her, everyone failed her. Every single person in her life. She was probably one person who could truly empathize with my mother when she had her own struggles. I don’t know for sure, but I know they shared some friendship and maybe the common ground for them was to be the women, whose life became all about being a caregiver to able and disabled bodied men.</p>

<p>So here I am remembering her to tell myself, that someone is thinking about her. Her life mattered in whatever little ways it did. Maybe it chisled a part of who I am.  I find it utterly depressing to accept that so much struggle for so little in life. <b>The life that wasn’t</b></p>

<p>I hope there were moments in your life that were happy and hopeful. And you are finally in a happy place, among people who only have love for you.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s post is about someone, whom I had not known or not kept in touch with. I had a neighbour when I was growing up. Someone of my mother’s age. I remember, every night she would howl as her drunk husband would beat her up. Year after year, life delivered pain and anguish. Many years later when I had moved away from that place, I found out that in an unfortunate accident her drunk husband fell from a height and passed away while he was visitng someone. She had a son, and she pegged her hopes on him to reclaim a life that never was.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/lifethatwasnt.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/lifethatwasnt.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Resurrected</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/21/resurrected/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resurrected" /><published>2025-10-21T16:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-21T16:17:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/21/resurrected</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/21/resurrected/"><![CDATA[<p>It has been long. When I left this blog to wither and decay, I did not assume I would need to visit it back. For a time it was my primary outlet of emotions that I needed to regulate. Even though I am in a better place and more resilient, it is difficult to change who I am. I need an outlet to periodically express myself and let the festering emotions out. So I am here, raking and resurrecting this place once again.</p>

<p>I hope this is the quiet room I can reflect, introspect and regurgitate in, on days that I can somehow brave, but the nights that would otherwise defeat me</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been long. When I left this blog to wither and decay, I did not assume I would need to visit it back. For a time it was my primary outlet of emotions that I needed to regulate. Even though I am in a better place and more resilient, it is difficult to change who I am. I need an outlet to periodically express myself and let the festering emotions out. So I am here, raking and resurrecting this place once again.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/resurrected.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/resurrected.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dormant</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/03/06/dormant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dormant" /><published>2024-03-06T05:02:27+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-06T05:02:27+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/03/06/dormant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/03/06/dormant/"><![CDATA[<p>I haven’t been here in a while. It has been a conscious choice. I have held myself back largely. There are several unpublished drafts that I don’t think I’ll publish now. In fact, I have been thinking about taking down this blog for good. I think it has run its course and served its purpose, to whatever extent it possibly can. I have to pay some money to run it everyday. I anyway cannot do that indefinitely and I don’t want to host it anywhere else.</p>

<p>I have mostly ok days. I am busy, occupied and going where my life will take me. Some parts have changed in my life, others I have made peace with. I do remain emotionally volatile and erupt now and then. But I hope thats almost like a volcano, possibly never going to go away only transition from active to dormant state. Thats life.</p>

<p>This is it, thanks for listening to me.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I haven’t been here in a while. It has been a conscious choice. I have held myself back largely. There are several unpublished drafts that I don’t think I’ll publish now. In fact, I have been thinking about taking down this blog for good. I think it has run its course and served its purpose, to whatever extent it possibly can. I have to pay some money to run it everyday. I anyway cannot do that indefinitely and I don’t want to host it anywhere else.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/dormant.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/dormant.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Irrational</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/16/irrational/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Irrational" /><published>2024-02-16T16:17:05+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-16T16:17:05+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/16/irrational</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/16/irrational/"><![CDATA[<p>I am out there somewhere. But not here. I have become so nervous about the weekends, that I go and numb myself with liquor even before they fully kick in. I finished a bottle of wine and ate a whole of pizza.</p>

<p>Today was a day, where you accidentally fall out of an airplane and then then somehow survive that but land into a bone crusher. Every news that I got incrementally since morning was worse than previous one. I feel sympathy for my boss and what he goes through on daily basis.</p>

<p>First, the work killed me. If you are the last straw to break the camel’s back do you hold it against yourself? I tried to do some good, but it was seen as too much intervention from me and someone I respect is affected by it. So much that they have chosen to leave the organisation. I have been debating whether I am responsible for that? My intentions were well placed and I am not a political person or at least I think so. Can I be wrong about everything? There is so much self doubt today. I feel like I have no mechanism to keep a check on myself. And I guess, I understand why people say that “leadership roles are very lonely”. Because unlike lot of roles, candid feedback is missing. People often won’t say anything. And you have to assume so much that it is easy to be a jerk and single minded or to be a pile of self doubt. Anyway, I don’t have a choice but to make my peace and move on. But this was not the worst. It was news after news and by the end of the day I felt like I should just sink into the ground and disappear.</p>

<p>I saw a dream last night. I saw I was visiting a ancestral house. An old lady lived there. She was affectionate to me and my kids. I had my whole family with me. A person came and sort of asked me these questions about how I knew her. I didn’t answer him clearly and then he sort of asked this leading question about if I could really forget the person who I knew her through? And I remembered who I knew her through. Lets call her S. I knew the old lady through S. He smiled and said, I knew you knew her through S and was just making sure you have not forgotten. Fucking mind and its mind games. Anyway, the lady was really sweet, we had a good time and she told us how she had aspirations in life. And then there was a window which allowed us to peek into her past. When I looked at it, I see that she was hit by something in her back and had a sever episode of cancer. And it took her a lot of years to recover. All her aspirations and life goals were put on a hold for that. She survived, but at what cost? She was happy but regretful about how things turned out. And we said out goodbyes and left.</p>

<p>So many things. S, my mom and so many subtle messages. I know my dreams are an immediate reflection of what goes in my mind. I won’t even try to interpret them.</p>

<p>She pinged me that she found a T shirt, that I said, I didn’t even realize I was missing. Did I really not realise that? It was one of my favourite and most comfortable night t shirt. Last time I left it, I think it was drenched in sweat at her place. Of course I remembered it. But I was hoping/thinking that not returning it was a conscious decision. Some part of me with some part of her. Just like a perfume bottle that I don’t use, but I smell time to time. Not for the smell of the perfume, but for the hands that held it. I don’t even care for the contents.</p>

<p>The day has just been a mess. I have three sips left to stare at the bottom of the bottle. And I cannot wait. Somedays I just feel lonely and there is no escaping that.</p>

<p>My situation at home has improved. It is not that I have not made effort, I have. But irrational love is irrational love. And sometimes you have to just accept that.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am out there somewhere. But not here. I have become so nervous about the weekends, that I go and numb myself with liquor even before they fully kick in. I finished a bottle of wine and ate a whole of pizza.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/irrational.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/irrational.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introspection</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/13/introspection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introspection" /><published>2024-02-13T18:15:48+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-13T18:15:48+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/13/introspection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/13/introspection/"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a month since I started tracking my mood to build a better understanding of whether I am on a path of recovery yet or not. Looking at the data I would say that the verdict is still not clear. I do feel that a week back I was lot more neutral and ok, but suddenly the last few days or a week has been difficult. Maybe this is what peaks and troughs look like and over time they will flatten. If I look closely, I can see the upward and downward slopes somewhere between those points.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/state-of-mind.jpeg" alt="image" /></p>

<p>What I do know is that I have not been travelling much and that sort of has kept me busy at home, however starting next week I will be travelling a lot more, sometimes across timezones. And I know travel aggravates loneliness. But hopefully I’ll manage it better this time around.</p>

<p>I do think my mind is actively working to help me tide over this. A lot of my dreams are worst case scenarios which sort of push me to move in a direction where I’ll start to actively move on. Sometimes I nitpick and find flaws that don’t exist to conceive incompatibilities that do not exist (or maybe do, since I am starting to become unsure about some things). I try to find reasons for hate, and while hate is impossible, it is an attempt to counterbalance my feelings. I have been thinking about finding people who can be just friends, meet and have a chat once in a while. I made my first attempt yesterday, lets see if it happens, I am far too unsure about meeting, but will take a leap of faith to reconnect with old friends who have grown out of touch. Have a friend visiting in early March, lets see how that goes, if I am back from my trip in time.</p>

<p>It just feels like, that my mind, this complex machinery is doing everything it can to nudge me and say “survive”.</p>

<p>Some days are better than the others, busy ones for sure. One of things I am quite happy about is that my work is back on track. I am focused, driven and unyielding. I hope it stays that way. But I am also not surprised, there has never been a crisis in my life, that affected my work for long. Work and financial stability is the foundation my life is somehow built upon. I take some sort of pride in that level of reliability. My whole mind is wired that way and thats exactly why my weekends are the hardest.</p>

<p>The news at work is not great, but my stress is much lower today. Mostly a neutral outlook. I think I even enjoyed listening to some songs. I even cooked for myself and ate something I like.</p>

<p>Hopefully tomorrow is going to be better.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been a month since I started tracking my mood to build a better understanding of whether I am on a path of recovery yet or not. Looking at the data I would say that the verdict is still not clear. I do feel that a week back I was lot more neutral and ok, but suddenly the last few days or a week has been difficult. Maybe this is what peaks and troughs look like and over time they will flatten. If I look closely, I can see the upward and downward slopes somewhere between those points.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/introspection.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/introspection.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Love letter</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/12/love-letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Love letter" /><published>2024-02-12T03:30:29+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-12T03:30:29+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/12/love-letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/02/12/love-letter/"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes I wonder why do I write everything that I write here? And then I stumbled on a letter that Richard Feynman wrote to his wife 16 months after she died. And it reminded me that sometimes we write for ourselves and not others.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I adore you, sweetheart.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>I know how much you like to hear that — but I don’t only &gt;write it because you like it — I write it because it &gt;makes me warm all over inside to write it to you.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>It is such a terribly long time since I last wrote to you &gt;— almost two years but I know you’ll excuse me because &gt;you understand how I am, stubborn and realistic; and I &gt;thought there was no sense to writing.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes I wonder why do I write everything that I write here? And then I stumbled on a letter that Richard Feynman wrote to his wife 16 months after she died. And it reminded me that sometimes we write for ourselves and not others.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/love-letter.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/love-letter.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>