<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-06T15:49:46+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Recovering melancholic</title><subtitle>Chronicles of a recovering melancholic</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Finger</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/finger/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finger" /><published>2025-11-06T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-06T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/finger</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/finger/"><![CDATA[<p>Today ended up being a tiring day. I reached home late. The work started early. One of the difficult meetings was sitting right in middle of the day. The one where just the thought of it sucks the hope and happiness out of you. Braved it. Skipped lunch. Thought that I’d grab something in evening. Got a call about a fall. Rushed to emergency. Vitals, scans, xrays. The usual. Ended up with a cast. Came back home just in time to resume work and calls. Remembered that in the morning I had planned to skip dinner and so there was no food. Grabbed a few odd things and then the chores for children. The day flew by. Nothing meaningful got done, the list of to-dos got longer, and body grew wearier.</p>

<p>In middle of all of that. I was chatting with someone about an incident that I was part of. I had written up the situation from my perspective. The reaction to that was, this is a one sided perspective. The other sided has not been represented. The view has been conviniently tailored to strengthen my representation. Surely, there is more to it if you ask the other person.</p>

<p>I pondered on it for a few minutes. Here was my response.</p>

<p>Sure. I am not a journalist. If people want to play the role of a protagonist, then they must write their own stories. Because, I am corupptible, greedy, insolent, biased and just human.</p>

<p>And if that is not justified enough a response, then I have only one finger to spare. However broken it may be.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today ended up being a tiring day. I reached home late. The work started early. One of the difficult meetings was sitting right in middle of the day. The one where just the thought of it sucks the hope and happiness out of you. Braved it. Skipped lunch. Thought that I’d grab something in evening. Got a call about a fall. Rushed to emergency. Vitals, scans, xrays. The usual. Ended up with a cast. Came back home just in time to resume work and calls. Remembered that in the morning I had planned to skip dinner and so there was no food. Grabbed a few odd things and then the chores for children. The day flew by. Nothing meaningful got done, the list of to-dos got longer, and body grew wearier.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/finger.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/finger.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Genesis</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/genesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Genesis" /><published>2025-11-06T01:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-06T01:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/genesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/06/genesis/"><![CDATA[<p>Back in cab, on my way to home. Reading old letters as I usually do at 1:30 am. Went far back when we were guessing names. I looked through the letters and I saw something that I missed as it was happening then.</p>

<p>Lookng back, I think this picture was the genesis of what we termed as “crash &amp; burn” eventually, even before it happened, from what <s>was</s> <i>could have been</i> a beautiful friendship.</p>

<p>The need to know more. The need to have more. The need to be more.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>He who is not contented with what he has, would not be contented with what he would like to have 
~Socrates</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Once of the excerpt from the letter that I enjoyed reading again.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We have graduated to life, my dear! (I have this habit of kissing the back of my right fist when I think about/talk to myself about someone who I have tender feelings for – only a couple of people in that list– I just did that writing the above sentence. That’s the sign)</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in cab, on my way to home. Reading old letters as I usually do at 1:30 am. Went far back when we were guessing names. I looked through the letters and I saw something that I missed as it was happening then.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/genesis.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/genesis.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Socks</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/05/socks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Socks" /><published>2025-11-05T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-05T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/05/socks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/05/socks/"><![CDATA[<p>There was a time when I wore only grey, black and white socks. Thick ones. Only specific brands. Mostly because I had skin sensitivity with general polyester brands. And then one day black socks started looking ugly to me. I could only deal with white and grey. But eventually moved to more colorful patterns. Maybe to represent a more versatile personality hidden under the garb of same old boring, in the plain sight.</p>

<p>One of the last things we fought about was the 4-5 pairs of socks that I received unceremoniously. I still remember how much it irked me to open that packet. Reflecting back it was less about socks. We had discussed numerous times, that in relationship, people have similar privileges. Everyone needs to express love and they have their own mechanisms. And either you can allow that freedom to express yourself even if the action to express that is in conflict with your personal principles or you can set specific boundaries. But it feels wierd if the rules are different for both people. A constant debate.</p>

<p>She expressed that she was particular. Her choice and sensibilities mattered. My choice and sensibilities could be overridden by her need to express love. It infuriated me. I failed to comprehend often, how could someone so smart, learnt, and empathetic could be so eccentric? She felt uneven setup was completely ok. What made it worse was that she would let me buy a few things every now and then with careful guidance to make me feel like that I had similar privileges.</p>

<p>When I looked at those socks, I said to myself, it has been so many years since I have worn black socks, I am never wearing these. I messaged her and told her that she was eccentric and she never really understood my perspective on it. And I was going to send these back to her. The bedsheet, towel(s), sweatshirt, handkerchiefs, shoes, underpants, toothbrush, soap, shirts; everything was laced with her personality on it. In someway, quite single mindedly. It didn’t even feel like a conversation at times, other times it did, because I resisted vehemently. The part that often irked me was the sense of superiority that came with those things. As if, she always knew better. I am not saying she didn’t. Thats beside the point, it is the arrogance that I was put off by.</p>

<p>And then the toothbrush stopped working suddenly one day. The bedsheet faded. The sweatshirt felt a bit loose. And I realized that slowly all those things were slowly fading away from my life. And then I found these socks. Still fresh, as black as they ever were and waiting on a decision from me. I decided, that when the time was there, I felt like I held my ground, and now was the time to change my mind. So I started wearing them. All my other socks have worn out. These are the primary socks I wear on most days. And everytime I look at them, they remind me of all this and confuse me. Was it really the fact that she failed to understand me on this point or was it my failed agency to accept and change? I don’t know. And now it does not matter.</p>

<p>Now, I can only <i>Sock it up!</i></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There was a time when I wore only grey, black and white socks. Thick ones. Only specific brands. Mostly because I had skin sensitivity with general polyester brands. And then one day black socks started looking ugly to me. I could only deal with white and grey. But eventually moved to more colorful patterns. Maybe to represent a more versatile personality hidden under the garb of same old boring, in the plain sight.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/socks.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/socks.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Content</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/03/content/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Content" /><published>2025-11-03T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-03T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/03/content</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/03/content/"><![CDATA[<p>Most days when I am down in the dumps I use this place to find my balance, vent out and generally spew hatred at the cosmos. However the days I am at peace, I tend to be an ungrateful prick and I don’t say much. So I thought maybe it is time to change it today.</p>

<p>While I am not at a point where I am thinking of this as a gratitude journal, even though I have enough in life to be grateful about, I think it is worth broadcasting to the void that I feel hopeful, calm and content.</p>

<p>Last few days were all about regurgigating months of pent up feelings. With all that unloaded into the abyss, I feel lighter and calmer.</p>

<p>It is easy to get tunnel-visioned on what you don’t have, to lose the sight of what you do. I remember I took this path to make best of what I have rather than what it could be. Today is a reminder of that.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most days when I am down in the dumps I use this place to find my balance, vent out and generally spew hatred at the cosmos. However the days I am at peace, I tend to be an ungrateful prick and I don’t say much. So I thought maybe it is time to change it today.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/content.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/content.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cycles</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/02/cycles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cycles" /><published>2025-11-02T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/02/cycles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/11/02/cycles/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been travelling. Came down to a house where I grew up in my teenage and adoloscent years. Memories rushing back from school and the time I spent in this house. I am here to be a caregiver for a person who has undergone a surgery.</p>

<p>Today seems to be generally a better day for me. Spent big part of it reflecting as to why do I operate in these cycles of hope and despair. This need for being loved and being free. Need for Solitude and detestation of lonliness. All this time the choices have always been with me and I have made them and then I have gone back to question them. Then why do I feel this lack of control? It just seems to be a perpetual cycle, like everything else in nature.</p>

<p>I was just flipping through old letters and reading the eternal promises of friendship I and she made, that seem to mean nothing now. One bound by resolution and other one by a strong sense of boundaries. Prioritising what is important to self than the other, possibly in both the cases.</p>

<p>If she put me to a test on this, what would I do? I have wondered. I am thinking about that and reflecting back on the letter I wrote to her few days back. Atleast the last part of it. Here is the paraphrased version of it.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I miss you. I am extremely sorry to have hurt you. I know I did. It is unforgivable and I understand that. Yet, I don’t think I will reach out and apologise. Apology has no meaning without amends. And I have no way or intention of making amends. I miss you because you were closest to someone I meaningfully loved in a long time. I could tell you everything. And I miss our conversation but I don’t miss the complexity of our lives. I feel free but also lonely. This is acceptable to me, on most days. Just that today is not that day. 
This is a very very selfish <i>I miss you</i>. If you came back and said that to me I wouldn’t be able to reciprocate. Like I had said, we were a perfect fit in some ways and not a fit in other. For things that are important to me in my life right now, I am not able to fit you in. And you deserve to be treated better and with more love. That is why I absolutely believe that I did the right thing by disappearing on you. Subjective and highly debatable. Sure.
I hope you are well baby (tears are rolling down just saying that word). Except an occasional reference I have not said that to anyone in such a long time. I miss saying that to you! You were such a joy! For this moment right now, I would give up everything to be with you. I miss you.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Ultimately, whenever I think about this topic of what role I have ended playing in the life of someone I genuinely cared about so much, the only rationalisation I have found for myself (mostly so that I can sleep peacefully at night) is</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It is ok to disappoint others if it means not disappointing yourself</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been travelling. Came down to a house where I grew up in my teenage and adoloscent years. Memories rushing back from school and the time I spent in this house. I am here to be a caregiver for a person who has undergone a surgery.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/cycle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/cycle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Future</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Future" /><published>2025-10-30T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-30T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/future</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/future/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Maybe I don’t exist in the future, I am so worried about</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maybe I don’t exist in the future, I am so worried about]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/future.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/future.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stranded</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/stranded/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stranded" /><published>2025-10-30T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-30T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/stranded</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/30/stranded/"><![CDATA[<p>I woke up with a numb mind. There was no plan to get out of the bed except the untimely work event that presented itself. That definitely got me moving but with a heavy heart and drudgingly slow mind.</p>

<p>Since then I have navigated my day with immense resistence. Feeling low and discouraged, I have been asking myself is this what rest of my life is going to be like? What can I do to change it?</p>

<p>How can I find contentment and peace, that eschews me so boldly? Do I need friends, do I need solitude, do I need purpose, do I need love, do I need people, do I need family, or do I just need to go back in time? Where did I cross over into this swamp of quicksand, where it takes immense effort to brave each day?</p>

<p>Sometimes I need a fresh start. Like, I need to be reborn. With new frame of mind, no baggage of the past, nothing to pull me down. And I need nourishment of love. But what is that love? Is it someone sitting next to me holding me? Is it physical? Is it someone just thinking about me? Is it someone who just cares about it? What is this elusive love that I keep looking for? How can I define it?</p>

<p>Just these questions ricocheting in my mind like a loose bullet. Everytime they hit a wall, it chips away a part of it. Overtime dismantling my sanity and I grow more and more frustrated with this lack of control on my life and my mind.</p>

<p>I want to go with the flow. But the flow won’t go with me. It is leaving me behind. Stranded and alone. I don’t think there is hope for me.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I woke up with a numb mind. There was no plan to get out of the bed except the untimely work event that presented itself. That definitely got me moving but with a heavy heart and drudgingly slow mind.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/stranded.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/stranded.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Liberated</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/29/liberated/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liberated" /><published>2025-10-29T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-29T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/29/liberated</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/29/liberated/"><![CDATA[<p>I was sleep deprived for last few days. Was travelling for work and returning to home in cab. Cab rides, remind me of me talking to her. The long chats we use to have and the frivilous things we use to say. The tired mind and lonely soul got sucked into the whirlwhind of memories.</p>

<p>In that moment, my mind was swirling with emotions. I felt reaching out and talking to her. Expressing how I was feeling. Contradictions were all over were me. I realized that I needed to let it all out but not at the cost of her or my sanity.</p>

<p>I figured for someone who has blocked me and cannot unblock me now, my letters would never be delivered to her. So I took a leap of faith and poured my heart out to her. Bared my soul into a letter. I shot it across into a void. Trembling with anxiety what if she read it? What if she received it?</p>

<p>Thankfully, atleast I think she did not, and it sits there in void. Capturing that moment of hopelessness for me. I can go back and read it. It was like capturing my emotions in a glass bottle and locking them away. Only to be admired momentarily every now and then.</p>

<p>I feel lighter having said everything that I wanted to. I feel happy to be able to say it to her and yet not to her. This is the best compromise I could have asked for. I don’t feel guilty, I don’t feel constrained.</p>

<p>I feel liberated, with a pseudo-void in my life, that is her. I don’t know how long this will last, but it works for now and that is more than what I can ask for. One step at a time.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was sleep deprived for last few days. Was travelling for work and returning to home in cab. Cab rides, remind me of me talking to her. The long chats we use to have and the frivilous things we use to say. The tired mind and lonely soul got sucked into the whirlwhind of memories.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/liberated.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/liberated.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">People</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/27/people/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People" /><published>2025-10-27T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-27T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/27/people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/27/people/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>You meet people for a reason. Either you need them to change your life or it is you who will change theirs</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You meet people for a reason. Either you need them to change your life or it is you who will change theirs]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/waiting.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/waiting.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Song In Heart</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/25/song-in-heart/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Song In Heart" /><published>2025-10-25T13:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-25T13:17:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/25/song-in-heart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/10/25/song-in-heart/"><![CDATA[<p>The sensor bell for his movement went off in the wee hours of the morning. I got up to help him and after helping him I found myself unable to go back to sleep. I ended up doomscrolling as usual.</p>

<p>Came across a song used as a background score by one of the videos on social media. It was a Tamil song by Iliayaaraja. This reminded me of a song that she once shared she me as one of her favourites. Unfortunately I didn’t remember the name or anything else about the song except a little context of what it was about. Thanks to the modern technology and its ability to deal with fuzzy asks, I was able to eventually find it. It was a song by Yesudas.</p>

<p>Since then the tune for both songs is stuck in my head reminding me of the long morning chats in general, over the phone before getting up. De-compressing and starting day with a conversation made mornings worth looking forward to. It has been so long that I have had a chat like that with anyone. These songs remind me of those rituals and her. Few days back I dreamt of her. I don’t remember the specifics but it was something in the context of her being indifferent to me on an airport.</p>

<p>It is funny how so many memories of her are all tied to travel, flights and airports and yet we were on an airport together maybe only once. And I remember that particular instance ended in both of us being distraught and sad. I am just glad we are not doing that to each other anymore. I continue to believe, this path has given certainty, closure and ability to move forward. Hopefully towards peace and maybe solitude.</p>

<p>One of the things a friend recently said, that helped me articulate it in a way, that I felt more at peace with it is</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Solitude is chosen, loneliness is not
~ A Friend</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sensor bell for his movement went off in the wee hours of the morning. I got up to help him and after helping him I found myself unable to go back to sleep. I ended up doomscrolling as usual.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/song-in-heart.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/song-in-heart.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>